Peter and Rose Krasnow
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Writings and Notes, circa 1916-1980, Series 3:; (Boxes 1-2; 1.3 linear feet)
  - By Others, circa 1929-1980, 3.3:
    - Essay - "A Psycho-Spiritual Approach to Culture," by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Essays and Other Writings, by Unidentified Author(s) (Probably by Glass, D. and T.S.), undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Essays and Diary, by Unidentified Author(s) (Probably by Herrera, J.F. and M.), 1932-1937, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Essay, by Unidentified Author(s) (Probably by Keefer, W.H. and A.), undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Essay, by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Essays - Unidentified, by Unidentified Author(s), undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Lectures - Grace Clements, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Lectures - Robert DeLuce, 1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Notes - Handwritten, by Unidentified Author(s), undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Notebook - Handwritten, by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Notes - Works Loaned to Claremont, by Unidentified Author, 1980 January 29 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Play - Esther, by Unidentified Author (Probably by W.P. Hayes), undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Play - Ruth, by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Play and Essay, by Unidentified Author (Probably by Hahn), undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Poetry, by Philip Noer, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Poetry, by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Radio Talks, by Grace Clements, 1954 April 8 - 1955 December 24, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Short Story - "The Absentrop Affair," by Alan C. Fox, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Short Story - "A Legend of Laangelo," by Irene M. Goldkind, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Short Story - "Twilight," by S. Miller, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Short Story, by Unidentified Author, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Typescript - God is a Little Girl, by E.D. Howe, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Typescript - Lorenzo, by Keenan, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Typescript (draft) - For Lorenzo (Loaned to Susan Ehrlich), 1978 October 3 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Typescript - A Skeleton Key to "Paterson," by Philip D. Noer, after 1966 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Diaries, circa 1955-1968, Series 4:; (Box 2-3; 5 folders)
  This series contains five handwritten diaries by Peter Krasnow.
  Diaries are arranged chronologically by date, if known. Two undated diaries are filed at the end of the series.
  - Handwritten - On Back of Typescript Pages, 1955 January - November (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Handwritten - On Back of Typescript Pages, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Handwritten - On Back of Typescript Pages, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Handwritten - On Back of Typescript Pages, March - July, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Personal Business Records, circa 1914-1982, Series 5:; (Box 3; 0.4 linear feet)
  This series contains Rose Krasnow's bank book from 1980, Peter Krasnow's naturalization certificate and passport, an inventory of paintings on index cards, tax applications for the Peter Krasnow Arts Foundation, materials relating to Peter Krasnow's estate and the purchase of his artwork, and various receipts.
  - Bank Book - Rose Krasnow, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Naturalization Certificate - Philip Reisberg (Peter Krasnow), 1914 July 17 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Painting Inventory (4x6 Cards), undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Passport - Peter Krasnow, 1931 October 9 - 1935 October 9 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Peter Krasnow Arts Foundation, 1980 December 10 - 1982 June 10 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Peter Krasnow Arts Foundation - Federal and State Tax Applications, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Peter Krasnow Estate - Alan C. Fox, 1980 December 19 - 1981 August 13 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Peter Krasnow Estate - Allan Cutrow Materials, 1980 March 27 - 1982 January 6, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Peter Krasnow Estate - Appraisal of Artwork 1/2, 1980 May 28 - 1980 June 2, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
  - Peter Krasnow Estate - Probate, 1980 March 27 - 1982 January 12 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Purchase of Peter Krasnow's Artwork, 1982 March 23 - April 1 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Receipts, 1934 January 1 - 1981 July 15 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Printed Materials, circa 1922-1981, Series 6:; (Boxes 3-4 and OV 9; 1.1 linear feet)
  This series contains exhibition catalogs, announcements, and invitations; clippings about Peter Krasnow and his work; bound books; magazines and journals, including The Argus, The Art Digest, The Menorah Journal, Arts and Architecture, and Archives of American Art Journal; an Oakland Museum brochure; a Chicago Society of Artists block print calendar; television and radio program guides; and two printed posters from Peter Krasnow's exhibit at the Galerie Pierre in 1934.
  The series is arranged as 6 subseries:
  6.1: Catalogs and Announcements, circa 1922-1981
  6.2: Clippings, circa 1923-1980
  6.3: Books, 1930-1974
  6.4: Published Magazines and Journals, 1924-1978
  6.5: Other, circa 1952 - 1974
  6.6: Printed Posters, 1934
  - Catalogs and Announcements, circa 1922-1981, 6.1:
    - Announcements, 1923 January 22 - 1975 March 23, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Catalogs - Peter Krasnow, Solo Exhibitions, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Catalogs - Peter Krasnow, Solo Exhibitions, 1929 February - 1975 March 23 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Catalogs - Peter Krasnow, Group Exhibitions, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Catalogs - Peter Krasnow, Group Exhibitions, 1922 April - 1927 April 8 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Catalogs - Peter Krasnow, Group Exhibitions, 1935 May 29 - 1981 December (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Catalogs - Other Artists, 1969 October 30 - 1972 August 6, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, circa 1923-1980, 6.2:
    - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1923 March 4 - 1931 December (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1934 March 1 - 1980 December 15 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Books, 1930-1974, 6.3:
    - Jews in American History, by Rabbi Maxwell H. Dubin, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - A Passing Dragon, by Lenore Kandel, 1959 January 10 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Peter Krasnow Drawings, 1967, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 29-30)
    - Edo - Thirty-Four Poems, by Arnold Chanin, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Habiru's The Story of Our Alphabet, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - A Little Book of Cheery Thoughts, edited by Barbara Wells Price, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Published Magazines and Journals, 1924-1978, 6.4:
    - American Forests - Peter Krasnow Article, Page 610, 1945 December (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - The Argus, Volume 1, Number 2, 1927 May (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Argus, Volume 3, Number 3 - Peter Krasnow Article, Page 5, 1928 June (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - The Argus, Volume 4, Number 3 - Peter Krasnow Article, Page 3, 1928 December (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Archives of American Art Journal, Volume 16, Number 1, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Archives of American Art Journal, Volume 18, Number 1 - Peter Krasnow, Page 30, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - The Art Digest, Volume 11, Number 17 - Peter Krasnow Article, Page 1, 1928 June (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - The Art Digest, Volume 4, Number 20 - Sadakichi Hartmann Article, Page 22, 1930 September (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Artforum - Peter Krasnow Article, Page 42, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Arts and Architecture - Peter Krasnow Article, Page 32, 1946 February (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - B'nai B'rith Magazine - Peter Krasnow Article, Page 126, 1931 January (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - California Arts and Architecture - Peter Krasnow Article, Page 18, 1944 January (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Carmel Pacific Spectator Journal, Volume 14, Number 4 - Edward Weston Article, 1957 September (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Deutsche Kunst und Dekoration - German Language Magazine, 1924 April (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Journal, Number 3 - Peter Krasnow Article, Page 51, 1974 December (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - The Menorah Journal, Volume 30, Number 1 - Peter Krasnow Article, Page 38, 1942 Winter, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
    - The Reconstructionist, 1950 February 10 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Topics of the Town, Volume 1, Number 12 - Image of Peter Krasnow Wood Carving, Page 7, 1930 August (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Other, circa 1952 - 1974, 6.5:
    - Prints of Peter Krasnow Watercolors, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Chicago Society of Artists Block Print Calendar, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Radio and Television Program Guides, 1954 April 4-17, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Brochure - The Oakland Museum, after 1974 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Printed Posters, 1934, 6.6:
    - Galerie Pierre - Peter Krasnow Exhibit, 1934 March 3 (Box 9 (OV))
- Artwork, circa 1918-1980, Series 7:; (Boxes 4-6, OV 7-8, 10; 1.5 linear feet)
  This series contains artwork, mostly by Peter Krasnow, including sketches and drawings, watercolors, oil studies, and prints. The sketches and drawings consist of landscapes, portraits, studies for paintings and sculpture, and abstract works. Watercolors include landscapes, still lifes, portraits, and other themes. The oil studies consist of thirty-three abstract works on board. There are seven prints, including four prints showing a wood engraving in various stages of completion.
  The series is arranged as 5 subseries:
  7.1: Sketches and Drawings, circa 1919-1980
  7.2: Watercolors, circa 1918-1943
  7.3: Oil Studies, 1940-1973
  7.4: Prints, circa 1928
  - Sketches and Drawings, circa 1919-1980, 7.1:
    - Pencil - Landscapes, circa 1919-1920 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Pencil Sketches, 1920-1929, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Pencil - Abstract, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Pencil - Oversized Drawings, 1922-1932, undated, (Oversized material housed in Box 6, F6) (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Pencil - Oversized Drawing, undated, (Oversized material housed in OV 7) (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Ink - A Book: Collection of Ink Drawings, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Ink Drawings, 1922-1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Ink - Abstract Drawings, 1977 November 5, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Ink - Portrait of Rose Krasnow, by Kaufman, 1980 November 3 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Ink - 3 Oversized Drawings, undated, (Oversized material housed in OV 10) (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Ink - 7 Oversized Drawings, 1942-1948, undated, (Oversized material housed in OV 8) (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Studies for Paintings and Sculpture, 1953-1955, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Pencil - 9 Oversized Drawings, 1922-1932, undated, (Oversized material from Box 4, F27) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Pencil - 1 Oversized Drawing, undated, (Oversized material from Box 4, F28) (Box 7 (OV))
    - Ink - 7 Oversized Drawings, 1942-1948, undated, (Oversized material from Box 4, F34) (Box 8 (OV))
    - Ink - 3 Oversized Drawings, undated, (Oversized material from Box 4, F33) (Box 10 (OV))
  - Watercolors, circa 1932-1943, 7.2:
    - Sketches, 1932-1934, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Watercolor of a Young Man, undated, (Oversized material housed in Box 6, F5) (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - 6 Watercolors, 1943, undated, (Oversized material housed in Box 6, F4) (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - 6 Watercolors, 1943, undated, (Oversized material from Box 4, F38) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Watercolor of a Young Man, undated, (Oversized material from Box 4, F37) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Oil Studies, 1940-1973, 7.3:
    - Oil Study on Board, 1940-1954, (6 folders) (Box 4, Folder 39-44)
    - Oil Study on Board (Labeled "The Camper"), 1954 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Oil Study on Board, 1955, (8 folders) (Box 4, Folder 46-53)
    - Oil Study on Board (Labeled "Strotium"), 1956 January 20 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Oil Study on Board, 1956 January 23 - 1973 October 19, (17 folders) (Box 5, Folder 2-18)
  - Prints, circa 1928, 7.4:
    - Prints, 1928, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Sketchbooks, circa 1918-1973, Series 8:; (Box 5; 5 folders)
  This series contains five sketchbooks. The first sketchbook, dated 1918-1931, consists of watercolor and pencil sketches. The second sketchbook, dated 1931-1933, consists of watercolor and pencil portraits. The third and fourth sketchbooks, both dated 1932-1933, were completed during Peter Krasnow's time living in France. The fifth sketchbook, dated 1966-1973, consists of pencil and ink sketches.
  - Sketchbook 1, 1918-1931 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Sketchbook 2 - Portraits, 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Sketchbook 3 - Watercolors, Dordogne, France, 1932-1933 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Sketchbook 4 - France, 1932-1933 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Sketchbook 5, 1966-1973 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Photographs, circa 1914-1981, Series 9:; (Boxes 5-6; 0.6 linear feet)
  Personal photographs depict Peter and Rose Krasnow, family, and friends, as well as a few scattered images of landscapes and architecture, possibly travel photographs. There are also photographs of Edward and Flora Weston. There are photographs of Peter Krasnow's paintings, drawings, and sculpture, and include two photo albums prepared by Susan Ehrlich for Peter and Rose Krasnow. An additional photo album includes images of Krasnow's relief sculptures for Sinai Temple's Kohn Chapel. Both the personal photographs and photographs of artwork include images by Dan Budnik.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  9.1: Personal Photographs, circa 1914-1981
  9.2: Photographs of Artwork, circa 1925-1979
  - Personal Photographs, circa 1914-1981, 9.1:
    - "Peter at the Western Wall. With Love Ivan Forbes," undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Family and Friends, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Family and Friends, 1914 - 1981 January (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Peter and Rose in Front of Studio, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1925-1979, 9.2:
    - Photographs of Drawings, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Photographs of Paintings, 1925-1978, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Photograph of Oil Painting, undated, (Oversized material housed in Box 6, F3) (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Photographs of Sculpture, November 15, 1962 - August, 1978, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Photographs of Paintings and Sculpture, 1974, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Photographs of Art in Studio, Home, and Gallery, 1961-1977, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Photo Album - Sinai Temple, Kohn Chapel, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Photo Albums Prepared by Susan Ehrlich, 1978 January 24 - 1979 June, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 36-37)
    - Negatives and Slides, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Photograph of Oil Painting, undated, (Oversized material from Box 5, F31) (Box 6, Folder 3)